<?xml version="1.0"?>
<mcarticles>
  <article id="1" title="A Memetic Algorithm for the University Course Timetabling Problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="2" title="A tabu history driven crossover operator design for memetic algorithm applied to Max-2SAT-problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="3" title="Multi-objective Memetic Approach for Flexible Process Sequencing Problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="4" title="Structure and Parameter Estimation for Cell Systems Biology Models" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="5" title="Finding consensus trees by evolutionary, variable neighborhood search, and hybrid algorithms" pages="323-330" loc="ISBN 978-1-60558-130-9" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="The consensus tree problem arises in the domain of phylogenetics and seeks to find for a given collection of trees a single tree best representing it. Usually, such a tree collection is obtained by biologists for a given taxa set either via different phylogenetic inference methods or multiple applications of a non-deterministic procedure. There exist various consensus methods which often have the drawback of being very strict, limiting the resulting consensus tree in terms of its resolution and/or precision. A reason for this typically is the coarse granularity of the tree metric used. To find fully resolved (binary) consensus trees of high quality, we consider the fine-grained TreeRank similarity measure and extend a previously presented evolutionary algorithm (EA) to a memetic algorithm (MA) by including different variants of local search using neighborhoods based on moves of single taxa as well as subtrees. Furthermore, we propose a variable neighborhood search (VNS) with an embedded variable neighborhood descent (VND) based on the same neighborhood structures. Finally sequential and intertwined combinations of the EA and MA with the VNS/VND are investigated. We give results on real and artificially generated data indicating in particular the benefits of the hybrid methods. " comment="" keywords="Pirkwieser, 2008"/>
  <article id="6" title="Genetic Local Search for Rule Learning" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="7" title="A memetic algorithm for the optimal winner determination problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="8" title="Design and analysis of stochastic local search for the multiobjective traveling salesman problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="9" title="The decomposition concept in handling the space allocation problem" pages="" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="The space allocation problem particularly in academic institutions is well known as a complex, difficult and time consuming task. In this paper, we discuss the application of the decomposition concept in handling the combinatorial optimization problem such as the university space allocation problem. In applying the decomposition, we introduce the bin and tuple concept. This method is found to simplify the entire problem and ease the problem solving process. Combined local search Memetic Algorithm is applied on the simplified problem. Combined local search refers to combination of optimum local searches for genetic operators in Memetic Algorithm. Nevertheless, without any restriction, other algorithms can be used on the simplified problem." comment="" keywords="Chandrakaisan, 2008"/>
  <article id="10" title="Memetic algorithm for intense local search methods using local search chains" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="11" title="Bi-objective memetic evolutionary algorithm for automated microwave filter synthesis" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="12" title="Two memetic algorithms for heterogeneous fleet vehicle routing problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="13" title="Memetic algorithm-based image watermarking scheme" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="14" title="A memetic algorithm for parallel batch machine scheduling with incompatible job families and dynamic job arrivals" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="15" title="A fuzzy solution based on Memetic algorithms for timetabling" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="16" title="Memetic algorithms with multi-local-search for resource allocation in multiuser OFDM based cognitive radio systems" pages="269-274" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Cognitive Radio (CR) is a novel concept for improving spectrum utilization in wireless communication systems by permitting secondary (unlicensed) users to access those frequency bands which are not currently being used by primary (licensed) users. A CR user has the ability to change its transmit parameters rapidly according to the environment it senses. Orthogonal frequency division multiplexing (OFDM) modulation is a good candidate for CR systems due to its flexibility in allocating resources among secondary users. In this paper, the design of a fast and efficient method for dynamically allocating subcarriers, transmit powers and bits to secondary users in a multiuser (MU) OFDM-based CR system is considered. A memetic algorithm (MA) combined with multi-local-search methods (MLS-MA) is proposed and shown to provide an improved performance over previously reported algorithms. [br]" comment="[br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In (Huang, 2008), Two local searches are defined: namely local search 1 and local search 2, and the selection of local search is purely random.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;table border=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Procedure&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;: Multi Local Search(x) &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]generate a random number within (0, 1) : &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]ran = random(0, 1); &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]If ran &amp;lt; k, do &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]x = Local Search1(x) ; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]else &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]x = Local Search2(x) ; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]end &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]return x ; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;" keywords="Huang, 2008"/>
  <article id="17" title="A memetic evolutionary search algorithm with variable length chromosome for rule extraction" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="18" title="A memetic algorithm for binary image reconstruction" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="19" title="A novel Memetic Algorithm based on real-observation quantum-inspired evolutionary algorithms" pages="486-490" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="To enhance the local search capability of quantum-inspired evolutionary algorithm, a novel Memetic Algorithm based on real-observation Quantuminspired evolutionary algorithms (MArQ) was proposed. MArQ is a hybrid algorithm combining QIEA with local search techniques. In MArQ, QIEA was used to explore the whole solution space and tabu search was employed to exploit the neighboring domains of the searched best solutions. Several bench complex functions and an application example of reactive power optimization in power systems were applied to test the MArQ performances. Experimental results show that MArQ is superior to the realobservation quantum-inspired evolutionary algorithm and several optimization algorithms reported, in terms of search capability and stability.  " comment="" keywords="Liu, 2008"/>
  <article id="20" title="Web document query optimization based on memetic algorithm" pages="53-56" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="To efficiently retrieve relevant documents from the explosive growth of the Internet and other sources of information access, an efficient document query optimization approach based on memetic algorithm(MA) is proposed. Experimental results show that the proposed algorithm can improve the precision of document retrieval compared with other conventional query optimization algorithm.[br]" comment="" keywords="Wang, 2008"/>
  <article id="21" title="Primer design with specific PCR product size using Memetic algorithm" pages="332-337" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="" comment="" keywords="Yang, 2008"/>
  <article id="22" title="Application of a memetic algorithm to the portfolio optimization problem" pages="512-521" loc="" type="article" year="2008" abstract="We use local search to improve the performance of Genetic Algorithms applied the problem of Financial Portfolio Selection and Optimization. Our work describes the Tree based Genetic Algorithm for Portfolio Optimization. To improve this evolutionary system, we introduce a new guided crossover operator, which we call the BWS, and add a local optimization step. The performance of the system increases noticeably on simulated experiments with historical data. " comment="" keywords="Aranha, 2008"/>
  <article id="23" title="A comparison of four different local search methods for solving vehicle routing problem with backhauls" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="24" title="An efficient ma-based classification rule mining algorithm" pages="702-705" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Classification rule mining is one of the important problems in the field of data mining which aims to extract a small set of rules from the training data set with predetermined targets. In this paper, an efficient classification rule mining algorithm is proposed by using memetic algorithm (MA). Experimental results show that the proposed classification algorithm achieves much better performance than the other related algorithms." comment="" keywords="Sun, 2008"/>
  <article id="25" title="Frequency modulation sound parameter identification using novel hybrid evolutionary algorithms" pages="67-72" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="The Frequency modulation sound parameter identification is a complex multimodal optimization problem. In this paper, we proposed four evolutionary hybrid algorithms to solve this problem. First we combine genetic algorithm (GA) and queen-bee algorithm (QB) with a random optimization method (RO) and generate Memetic and QB-Memetic hybrid algorithms, respectively; then modified Nelder-Mead simplex algorithm (MNM) combine with particle swarm optimization (PSO) and differential evolution (DE) algorithms and generate MNM-PSO and MNM-DE hybrid algorithms, respectively. The proposed algorithms are compared in terms of three measures: success rate, average values of the cost function in all successful runs, and the minimum cost in 20 runs. The obtained results demostrate the proposed hybrid algorithms have the better performance than their non-hybrid competitors in the most times. Also The PSO has the best minimum and average value of the cost function and the MNM-PSO has the best success rate. [br]" comment="" keywords="Baghmisheh, 2008"/>
  <article id="26" title="A MA-based web document classification algorithm" pages="952-955" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="The amount of online document has grown greatly in recent years due to the increase in popularity of the World Wide Web. Thus, developing an efficient document classification method to automatically manipulate Web document is of great importance. A novel memetic algorithm(MA)-based document classification algorithm is presented in this paper. The experimental results show that the proposed algorithm achieves much better performance than other related classification algorithms [br]" comment="" keywords="Sun, 2008"/>
  <article id="27" title="An efficient Web query optimization algorithm based on LDA and MA" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="28" title="A modified shuffled frog leaping algorithm for optimal tuning of multivariable PID controllers" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="29" title="Countering poisonous inputs with memetic neuroevolution" pages="610-619" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Applied to certain problems, neuroevolution frequently gets stuck in local optima with very low fitness; in particular, this is true for some reinforcement learning problems where the input to the controller is a high-dimensional and/or ill-chosen state description. Evidently, some controller inputs are &amp;quot;poisonous&amp;quot;, and their inclusion induce such local optima. Previously, we proposed the memetic climber, which evolves neural network topology and weights at different timescales, as a solution to this problem. In this paper, we further explore the memetic climber, and introduce its population-based counterpart: the memetic ES. We also explore which types of inputs are poisonous for two different reinforcement learning problems.  " comment="" keywords="Togelius, 2008"/>
  <article id="30" title="A memetic algorithm for the delineation of local labour markets" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="31" title="Development of a memetic algorithm for dynamic multi-objective optimization and its applications for online neural network modeling of UAVs" pages="548-554" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Dynamic Multi-objective Optimization (DMO) is one of the most challenging class of optimization problems where the objective functions change over time and the optimization algorithm is required to identify the corresponding Pareto optimal solutions with minimal time lag. DMO has received very little attention in the past and none of the existing multi-objective algorithms perform satisfactorily on test problems and a handful of such applications have been reported. In this paper, we introduce a Memetic Algorithm (MA) and illustrate its performance for online Neural Network (NN) identification of the Multi-Input Multi-Output Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) system. As a typical case, the longitudinal model of the UAV is considered and the performance of a NN trained with the memetic algorithm is compared to another trained with Levenberg-Marquardt training algorithm using mini-batches. The memetic algorithm employs an orthogonal epsilon-constrained formulation to deal with multiple objectives and a Sequential Quadratic Programming (SQP) solver is embedded as its local search mechanism to improve the rate of convergence. The performance of the memetic algorithm is presented for two benchmarks Fisher\'s Discriminant Analysis (FDA), FDA1 and modified FDA2 before highlighting its benefits for online NN model identification for UAVs. Observations from our recent work [1] indicated that Mean Square Error (MSE) alone may not always be a good measure for training the networks. Hence the MSE and maximum absolute value of the instantaneous error is considered as objectives to be minimized which requires a Dynamic MO algorithm. The proposed memetic algorithm is aimed to solve such identification problems and the same can be extended to control problems." comment="" keywords="Isaacs, 2008"/>
  <article id="32" title="Evolving both size and accuracy of RBF networks using Memetic Algorithm" pages="1938-1944" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="One of the main obstacles to obtain an artificial neural network with reasonable performance is the parameter setting. This work proposes a methodology to the automatic definition of RBF (Radial Basis Function) networks with an appropriate configuration for the selected classification problems. We propose the use of a Memetic Algorithm in order to perform the search for networks with minimum architecture and error rate. A set of experiments was made with four datasets and we were able to show the effectiveness of the method. " comment="" keywords="Silva, 2008"/>
  <article id="33" title="Application of Memetic Differential Evolution frameworks to PMSM drive design" pages="2113-2120" loc="" type="article" year="2008" abstract="This paper proposes the application of Memetic Algorithms employing Differential Evolution as an evolutionary framework in order to achieve optimal design of the control system for a permanent-magnet synchronous motor. Two Memetic Differential Evolution frameworks have been considered in this paper and their performance has been compared to a standard Differential Evolution, a standard Genetic Algorithm and a Memetic Algorithm presented in literature for solving the same problem. All the algorithms have been tested on a simulation of the whole system (control system and plant) using a model obtained through identification tests. Numerical results show that the Memetic Differential Evolution frameworks seem to be very promising in terms of convergence speed and has fairly good performance in terms of final solution detected for the realworld problem under examination. In particular, it should be remarked that the employment of a meta-heuristic local search component during the early stages of the evolution seems to be very beneficial in terms of algorithmic efficiency." comment="" keywords="Caponio, 2008"/>
  <article id="35" title="The \&quot;natura non facit saltus\&quot; principle in memetic computing" pages="" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="This paper proposes the employment of continuous probability distributions instead of step functions for adaptive coordination of the local search in fitness diversity based Memetic Algorithms. Two probability distributions are considered in this study: the beta and exponential distributions. These probability distributions have been tested within two memetic frameworks present in literature. Numerical results show that employment of the probability distributions can be beneficial and improve performance of the original Memetic Algorithms on a set of test functions without varying the balance between the evolutionary and local search components. " comment="basically compare and summarize the adaptive memetic algorithms such as the memetic differential evolution algorithm and the fast adaptive memetic algorithm. The paper is similar the review paper (Neri, 2008)" keywords="Tirronen, 2008"/>
  <article id="36" title="A fast adaptive memetic algorithm for on-line and off-line control design of PMSM drives" pages="28-41" loc="Volume 37, Issue 1" type="article" year="2007" abstract="In this paper fast adaptive memetic algorithm (FAMA) is proposed which is used to design the optimal control system for a permanent-magnet synchronous motor. The FAMA is a memetic algorithm with a dynamic parameter setting and two local searchers adaptively launched, either one by one or simultaneously, according to the necessities of the evolution. The FAMA has been tested for both offline and online optimization. The former is based on a simulation of the whole system - control system and plant - using a model obtained through identification tests. The online optimization is model free because each fitness evaluation consists of an experimental test on the real motor drive. The proposed algorithm has been compared with other optimization approaches, and a matching analysis has been carried out offline and online. Excellent results are obtained in terms of optimality, convergence, and algorithmic efficiency. Moreover, the FAMA has given very robust results in the presence of noise in the experimental system." comment=" " keywords="Caponio, 2007"/>
  <article id="37" title="A memetic algorithm for maximizing net present value in resource-constrained project scheduling problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="38" title="An Immune Inspired Memetic Algorithm for power distribution system design under load evolution uncertainties" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="39" title="Memetic algorithm for dynamic resource allocation in multiuser OFDM based cognitive radio systems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="40" title="Learning what to ignore: Memetic climbing in topology and weight space" pages="3274-3281" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="We present the memetic climber, a simple search algorithm that learns topology and weights of neural networks on different time scales. When applied to the problem of learning control for a simulated racing task with carefully selected inputs to the neural network, the memetie climber outperforms a standard hill-climber. When inputs to the network are less carefully selected, the difference is drastic. We also present two variations of the memetie climber and discuss the generalization of the underlying principle to population-based neuroevolution algorithms." comment="" keywords="Togelius, 2008"/>
  <article id="41" title="Simple scheduled memetic algorithm for inverse problems in higher dimensions: Application to chemical kinetics" pages="3905-3912" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="This paper proposes a scheme for the hybridisation of an Evolution Strategy framework and periodically scheduled Nelder-Mead algorithm. This relatively simple hybridisation scheme turns out to be efficient for the optimisation problems in higher dimensions. The efficiency of the proposed method is tested for a complex engineering problem, namely an inverse problem of chemical kinetics. An extensive parameter analysis and tuning are presented. Numerical results show the superiority of the proposed methods in comparison with some popular metaheuristics and some tailored algorithms presented in the literature for solving the problem under investigation." comment="" keywords="Kononova, 2008"/>
  <article id="42" title="Memetic algorithms for feature selection in face recognition" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="43" title="Memetic Pareto Evolutionary artificial neural networks for the determination of growth limits of listeria monocytogenes" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="44" title="A Study of the effects of clustering and local search on Radio Network Design evolutionary computation approaches" pages="951-954" loc="ISBN 978-0-7695-3326-1" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="The goal of this paper is twofold. First, we want to make a study about how evolutionary computation techniques can efficiently solve the radio network design problem. For this goal we test several evolutionary computation techniques within the OPLINK experimental framework and compare them. Second, we propose a clustering approach and a 2-OPT in order to improve the results obtained by the evolutionary algorithms. Experiments carried out provide empirical evidence of how clustering-based techniques help in improving all algorithms tested. Extensive computational tests, including ones without clustering and 2-OPT, are performed with three evolutionary algorithms: genetic algorithms, memetic algorithms and chromosome appearance probability matrix algorithms." comment="2-Opt" keywords="Saez, 2008"/>
  <article id="45" title="Adaptive pattern nulling design of linear array antenna by phase-only perturbations using memetic algorithms" pages="308-311" loc="ISBN 0-7695-2616-0" type="inproceedings" year="2006" abstract="In this paper, the pattern nulling of a linear array for interference cancellation is derived by phase-only perturbations using memetic algorithms (MAs). The MAs uses improvement procedures which is obtained by incorporating local search into the genetic algorithms. It is proposed to improve the search ability of genetic algorithms. MA is a kind of an improved type of the traditional genetic algorithms. By using local search procedure, it can avoid the shortcoming of the traditional genetic algorithms, whose termination criteria are set up by using the trial and error method. The MA is applied to find the pattern nulling of the proposed adaptive antenna. This design for radiation pattern nulling of an adaptive antenna can suppress interference by placing a null at the direction of the interfering source, i.e. to increase the signal, to interference ratio. This proposed method is that an innovative adaptive antenna optimization technique is also able to solve the multipath problem which exists in practical wireless communication systems. Two examples are provided to justify the proposed phase-only perturbations approach based on MAs. Computer simulation results are given to demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed method. " comment="" keywords="Hsu, 2006"/>
  <article id="46" title="A watermarking algorithm based on MA and DWT" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="47" title="Wireless Sensor Network deployment using a Memetic Simulated Annealing" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="48" title="Multicriteria optimization for ABC inventory classification" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="49" title="Improvements to the bacterial memetic algorithm used for fuzzy rule base extraction" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="50" title="An improved genetic algorithm for the extended capacitated arc routing problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="51" title="Performance evaluation and comparison and improvement of standard cell placement techniques in VLSI design" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="52" title="Efficient batch job scheduling in grids using cellular memetic algorithms" pages="1-8" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="Due to the complex nature of Grid systems, the design of efficient Grid schedulers is challenging since such schedulers have to be able to optimize many conflicting criteria in very short periods of time. This problem has been tackled in the literature by several different meta-heuristics, and our main focus in this work is to develop a new highly competitive technique with respect to the existing ones. For that, we exploit the capabilities of Cellular Memetic Algorithms, a kind of Memetic Algorithm with structured population, for obtaining efficient batch schedulers for Grid systems, and the resulting scheduler is experimentally tested through a Grid simulator." comment="" keywords="Xhafa, 2007"/>
  <article id="53" title="An Evolutionary Algorithm with Distance Measure for the Split Delivery Capacitated Arc Routing Problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="54" title="Heuristics and meta-heuristics for lot sizing and scheduling in the soft drinks industry A comparison study" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="55" title="Memetic Algorithms for Optimizing Adaptive Linear Array Patterns by Phase-Position Perturbation" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="56" title="Human-competitive lens system design with evolution strategies" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="57" title="Memetic algorithm based on a constraint satisfaction technique for VRPTW" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="58" title="A memetic algorithm for evolutionary prototype selection: A scaling up approach" pages="2693-2709" loc="Volume 41, Number 8" type="article" year="2008" abstract="Prototype selection problem consists of reducing the size of databases by removing samples that are considered noisy or not influential on nearest neighbour classification tasks. Evolutionary algorithms have been used recently for prototype selection showing good results. However, due to the complexity of this problem when the size of the databases increases, the behaviour of evolutionary algorithms could deteriorate considerably because of a lack of convergence. This additional problem is known as the scaling up problem. Memetic algorithms are approaches for heuristic searches in optimization problems that combine a population-based algorithm with a local search. In this paper, we propose a model of memetic algorithm that incorporates an ad hoc local search specifically designed for optimizing the properties of prototype selection problem with the aim of tackling the scaling up problem. In order to check its performance, we have carried out an empirical study including a comparison between our proposal and previous evolutionary and non-evolutionary approaches studied in the literature. The results have been contrasted with the use of non-parametric statistical procedures and show that our approach outperforms previously studied methods, especially when the database scales up. " comment="" keywords="Garcia, 2008"/>
  <article id="59" title="Pareto memetic algorithm for multiple objective optimization with an industrial application" pages="313--333" loc="Volume 14, Number 4" type="article" year="2008" abstract="Multiple objective combinatorial optimization problems are difficult to solve and often, exact algorithms are unable to produce optimal solutions. The development of multiple objective heuristics was inspired by the need to quickly produce acceptable solutions. In this paper, we present a new multiple objective Pareto memetic algorithm called PMSMO. The PMSMO algorithm incorporates an enhanced fine-grained fitness assignment, a double level archiving process and a local search procedure to improve performance. The performance of PMSMO is benchmarked against state-of-the-art algorithms using 0-1 multi-dimensional multiple objective knapsack problem from the literature and an industrial scheduling problem from the aluminum industry. " comment="&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In (Zinflou, 2008), two local searches are retained: the 3-Opt limited arc exchange method (Johnson and McGeoch 1997) and the Or-Opt method (Or 1976).[br]In PMSMO, a movement from a solution &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;x&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; towards a neighboring solution &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;y&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is carried out in both cases. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;First, if the neighboring solution &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;y&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; dominates the starting solution &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;x&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; then a movement is carried out. If, on the contrary, there is no dominance relationship between &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;x&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;y&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;, for each generation, a weight &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;w_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is determined randomly, where the sum of the weights &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;w_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is equal to 1 for each of the objectives &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; of the problem to be solved. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The random determination of the weights orients the search in different directions for each generation. The authors then calculate the normalized value &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;n&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; according to[br]the definition:&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;m&amp;gt;n=prod{i=1}{m}({y_i} / {x_i})^{w_i}&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;where &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;m&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; represents the total number of objectives. In the context of a minimization, if &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;n&amp;lt;1&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; a movement is carried out. In the contrary case, no movement is carried out.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br]" keywords="Zinflou, 2008"/>
  <article id="60" title="Discrete tomography reconstruction through a new memetic algorithm" pages="347-352" loc="" type="article" year="2008" abstract="Discrete tomography is a particular case of computerized tomography that deals with the reconstruction of objects made of just one homogeneous material, where it is sometimes possible to reduce the number of projections to no more than four. Most methods for standard computerized tomography cannot be applied in the former case and ad hoc techniques must be developed to handle so few projections. " comment="2-Opt" keywords="Gesu, 2008"/>
  <article id="61" title="Efficient local search limitation strategies for vehicle routing problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="62" title="Hybridizations of metaheuristics with branch and bound derivates" pages="85-116" loc="" type="article" year="2008" abstract="An important branch of hybrid metaheuristics concerns the hybridization with branch and bound derivatives. In this chapter we present examples for two different types of hybridization. The first one concerns the use of branch and bound features within construction-based metaheuristics in order to increase their efficiancy. The second example deals with the use of a metaheuristic, in our case a memetic algorithm, in order to increase the efficiancy of branch and bound, respectively branch and bound derivatives such as beam search. The quality of the resulting hybrid techniques is demonstrated by means of the application to classical string problems: the longest common subsequence problem and the shortest common supersequence problem. " comment="" keywords="Blum, 2008"/>
  <article id="63" title="A niching memetic algorithm for simultaneous clustering and feature selection" pages="868-879" loc="Volume 20, Number 7" type="article" year="2008" abstract="Clustering is inherently a difficult task and is made even more difficult when the selection of relevant features Is also an issue. In this paper, we propose an approach for simultaneous clustering and feature selection using a niching memetic algorithm. Our approach (which we call NMA$\\_$CFS) makes feature selection an integral part of the global clustering search procedure and attempts to overcome the problem of identifying less promising locally optimal solutions in both clustering and feature selection, without making any a priori assumption about the number of clusters. Within the NMA-CFS procedure, a variable composite representation is devised to encode both feature selection and cluster centers with different numbers of clusters. Furthermore, local search operations are introduced to refine feature selection and cluster centers encoded In the chromosomes. Finally, a niching method is integrated to preserve the population diversity and prevent premature convergence. In an experimental evaluation, we demonstrate the effectiveness of the proposed approach by using both synthetic and real data." comment="" keywords="Sheng, 2008"/>
  <article id="64" title="Memetic algorithm for the generalized asymmetric traveling salesman problem" pages="199-210" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="The generalized traveling salesman problem (GTSP) is an extension of the well-known traveling salesman problem. In GTSP, we are given a partition of cities into groups and we are required to find a minimum length tour that includes exactly one city from each group. The aim of this paper is to present a new memetic algorithm for GTSP which clearly outperforms the state-of-the-art memetic algorithm of Snyder and Daskin [21] with respect to the quality of solutions. Computational experiments conducted to compare the two heuristics also show that our improvements come at a cost of longer running times, but the running times still remain within reasonable bounds (at most a few minutes). While the Snyder-Daskin memetic algorithm is designed only for the Symmetric GTSP, our algorithm can solve both symmetric and asymmetric instances. Unlike the Snyder-Daskin heuristic, we use a simple machine learning approach as well." comment="" keywords="Gutin, 2007"/>
  <article id="65" title="An order based memetic evolutionary algorithm for set partitioning problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="66" title="Local search with quadratic approximations into memetic algorithms for optimization with multiple criteria" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="67" title="Multiobjective hybrid optimization and training of recurrent neural networks" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="68" title="An AM radio receiver designed with a genetic algorithm based on a bacterial conjugation genetic operator" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="69" title="A memetic algorithm for graph coloring" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="70" title="A hybrid genetic - Particle Swarm Optimization Algorithm for the vehicle routing problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="71" title="An evolutionary memetic algorithm for rule extraction" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="72" title="Memetic variation local search vs. life-time learning in electrical impedance tomography" pages="615-624" loc="ISBN 978-3-642-01128-3" type="inproceedings" year="2009" abstract="In this paper, various metaheuristics for a numerical optimization problem with application to Electric Impedance Tomography are tested and compared. The experimental setup is composed of a real valued Genetic Algorithm,the Differential Evolution, a self adaptive Differential Evolution recently proposed in literature, and two novelMemetic Algorithms designed for the problem under study. The two proposed algorithms employ different algorithmic philosophies in the field of Memetic Computing. The first algorithm integrates a local search into the operations of the offspring generation, while the second algorithm applies a local search to individuals already generated in the spirit of life-time learning. Numerical results show that the fitness landscape and difficulty of the optimization problem heavily depends on the geometrical configuration, as well the proposed Memetic Algorithms seem to be more promising when the geometrical conditions make the problem harder to solve." comment="" keywords="Leskinen, 2009"/>
  <article id="73" title="A multi-objective approach for robust airline scheduling" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="We present a memetic approach for multi-objective improvement of robustness influencing features (called robustness objectives) in airline schedules. Improvement of the objectives is obtained by simultaneous flight retiming and aircraft rerouting, subject to a fixed fleet assignment. Approximations of the Pareto optimal front are obtained by applying a multi-meme memetic algorithm. We investigate biased meme selection to encourage exploration of the boundaries of the search space and compare it with random meme selection. An external population of high quality solutions is maintained using the adaptive grid archiving algorithm. The presented approach is applied to investigate simultaneous improvement of reliability and flexibility in real world schedules from KLM Royal Dutch Airlines. Experimental results show that the approach enables us to obtain schedules with significant improvements for the considered objectives. A large scale simulation study was undertaken to quantify the influence of the robustness objectives on the operational performance of the schedules. Rigorous sensitivity analysis of the results shows that the influence of the schedule reliability is dominant and that increased schedule flexibility could improve the operational performance." comment="" keywords="Burke, 2009"/>
  <article id="74" title="Determining optimum queue length in computer networks by using memetic algorithms" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="75" title="Memetic differential evolution frameworks in filter design for defect detection in paper production" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="76" title="Fuzzy controller design using a new shuffled frog leaping algorithm" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="77" title="A hybrid memetic algorithm for maximizing the weighted number of just-in-time jobs on unrelated parallel machines" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="78" title="Scale factor local search in differential evolution" pages="153-171" loc="Volume 1, Number 2" type="article" year="2009" abstract="This paper proposes the scale factor local search differential evolution (SFLSDE). The SFLSDE is a differential evolution (DE) based memetic algorithm which employs, within a self-adaptive scheme, two local search algorithms. These local search algorithms aim at detecting a value of the scale factor corresponding to an offspring with a high performance, while the generation is executed. The local search algorithms thus assist in the global search and generate offspring with high performance which are subsequently supposed to promote the generation of enhanced solutions within the evolutionary framework. Despite its simplicity, the proposed algorithm seems to have very good performance on various test problems. Numerical results are shown in order to justify the use of a double local search instead of a single search. In addition, the SFLSDE has been compared with a standard DE and three other modern DE based metaheuristic for a large and varied set of test problems. Numerical results are given for relatively low and high dimensional cases. A statistical analysis of the optimization results has been included in order to compare the results in terms of final solution detected and convergence speed. The efficiency of the proposed algorithm seems to be very high especially for large scale problems and complex fitness landscapes. " comment="&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The local search in (Neri, 2009) is applied to optimize the scale factor of DE, the scale factor &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;F&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is used during the crossover of DE to control its jump. The local search consists of two local searchers: namely Golden Section Search and Hill Climbing. During each iteration, the offspring solution &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;x_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is obtained using the DE crossover and the scale factor &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;F&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;, if &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;x_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is the best, a probability &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;rho&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is applied to randomly select Golden Section Search or Hill Climbing as the local search to be applied to &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;F&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The fitness &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;f(F)&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; must be defined for the local search to identify the better scale factor in the neighborhood of current scale factor. the paper use the following procedure to compute &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;f(F)&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;table border=&amp;quot;1&amp;quot;&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;tr&amp;gt;&amp;lt;td&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;Procedure::&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;Compute &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;f(F)&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;BEGIN&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;m&amp;gt;v=x_t + F(x_{r1} - x_{r2})&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;m&amp;gt;u=crossover(x_t, x_{r3})&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;lt;m&amp;gt;return&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;f(F)=fitness(u)&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;; &amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;b&amp;gt;END&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;&amp;lt;br /&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;/td&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/tr&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;/table&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;where &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;u&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is the offspring solution produced using DE crossover and the scale factor &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;F&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;, and &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;f(F)=fitness(u)&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; where &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;fitness(u)&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is the fitness of the offspring solution &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;u&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;. The local search choice probability &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;rho&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; seems is predefined value, therefore the LS selection is random.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;" keywords="Neri, 2009"/>
  <article id="79" title="Evolution and incremental learning in the iterated prisoner[quot]s dilemma" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="80" title="A hybrid metaheuristic case-based reasoning system for nurse rostering" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="81" title="Integrating cross-dominance adaptation in multi-objective memetic algorithms" pages="325-351" loc="Volume 171" type="article" year="2009" abstract="This chapter proposes a novel adaptive memetic approach for solving multi-objective optimization problems. The proposed approach introduces the novel concept of crossdominance and employs this concept within a novel probabilistic scheme which makes use of the Wigner distribution for performing coordination of the local search. Thus, two local searchers are integrated within an evolutionary framework which resorts to an evolutionary algorithm previously proposed in literature for solving multi-objective problems. These two local searchers are a multi-objective version of simulated annealing and a novel multi-objective implementation of the Rosenbrock algorithm. Numerical results show that the proposed algorithm is rather promising and, for several test problems, outperforms two popular meta-heuristics present in literature. A realworld application in the field of electrical engineering, the design of a control system of an electric motor, is also shown. The application of the proposed algorithm leads to a solution which allows successful control of a direct current motor by simultaneously handling the conflicting objectives of the dynamic response. " comment="" keywords="Caponio, 2009"/>
  <article id="82" title="A memetic algorithm with adaptive hill climbing strategy for dynamic optimization problems" pages="763-780" loc="Volume 13, Number 8-9" type="article" year="2009" abstract="Dynamic optimization problems challenge traditional evolutionary algorithms seriously since they, once converged, cannot adapt quickly to environmental changes. This paper investigates the application of memetic algorithms, a class of hybrid evolutionary algorithms, for dynamic optimization problems. An adaptive hill climbing method is proposed as the local search technique in the framework of memetic algorithms, which combines the features of greedy crossover-based hill climbing and steepest mutation-based hill climbing. In order to address the convergence problem, two diversity maintaining methods, called adaptive dual mapping and triggered random immigrants, respectively, are also introduced into the proposed memetic algorithm for dynamic optimization problems. Based on a series of dynamic problems generated from several stationary benchmark problems, experiments are carried out to investigate the performance of the proposed memetic algorithm in comparison with some peer evolutionary algorithms. The experimental results show the efficiency of the proposed memetic algorithm in dynamic environments." comment="" keywords="Wang, 2009"/>
  <article id="83" title="A case study of memetic algorithms for constraint optimization" pages="351-360" loc="ISBN 978-3-540-73728-5" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="There is a variety of knapsack problems in the literature. Multidimensional0-1 knapsack problem (MKP) is an NP-hard combinatorial optimizationproblem having many application areas. Many approaches have been proposed forsolving this problem. In this paper, an empirical investigation of memetic algorithms(MAs) that hybridize genetic algorithms (GAs) with hill climbing for solving MKPsis provided. Two distinct sets of experiments are performed. During the initial experiments, MA parameters are tuned. GA and four MAs each using a different hillclimbing method based on the same configuration are evaluated. In the second set ofexperiments, a self-adaptive (co-evolving) multimeme memetic algorithm (MMA) iscompared to the best MA from the parameter tuning experiments. MMA utilizes theevolutionary process as a learning mechanism for choosing the appropriate hill climbingmethod to improve a candidate solution at a given time. Two well-known MKPbenchmarks are used during the experiments." comment="Reason for singling out this paper is because the paper perform random selection of crossover as the crossover. although not applying to the individual learning phase, if we take the meme definition broadly, this multi-crossover MA may fit the category.[br]" keywords="Liu, 2007"/>
  <article id="84" title="Non-genetic transmission of memes by diffusion" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="85" title="Use of Heuristic Local Search for Single-Objective Optimization in Multiobjective Memetic Algorithms" pages="743-752" loc="ISBN 978-3-540-87699-1" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="This paper proposes an idea of using heuristic local search procedures specific for single-objective optimization in multiobjective genetic local search (MOGLS). A large number of local search techniques have been studied for various combinatorial optimization problems. Thus we may have a situation where a powerful local search procedure specific for a particular objective is available in multiobjective optimization. Such a local search procedure, however, can improve only a single objective. Moreover, it may have severe side-effects on the other objectives. For example, in a scheduling problem, an insertion move of a job with the maximum delay to an earlier position in a current schedule is likely to improve only the maximum tardiness. In this paper, we assume a situation where each objective has its own heuristic local search procedure. First we explain our MOGLS algorithm, which is the hybridization of NSGA-II and weighted sum-based local search. Next we propose an idea of using heuristic local search procedures specific for single-objective optimization in MOGLS. Then we implement the proposed idea as a number of variants of MOGLS. These variants are different from each other in the choice of a heuristic local search procedure. We examine three schemes: random, probabilistic and deterministic. Finally we examine the performance of each variant through computational experiments on multiobjective 0/1 knapsack problems with two, three and four objectives. It is shown that the use of heuristic local search procedures and their appropriate choice improve the performance of MOGLS." comment="" keywords="Ishibuchi, 2008"/>
  <article id="86" title="A memetic algorithm for the probabilistic traveling salesman problem" pages="146-152" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="The probabilistic traveling salesman problem (PTSP) is an important theoretical and practical topic in the study of stochastic network problems. It provides researchers with a modeling framework for exploring the stochastic effects in routing problems. This paper focuses on developing a memetic algorithm (MA) by incorporating the nearest neighbor algorithm to generate initial solutions, 1-shift and/or 2-opt exchanges for local search, and edge recombination (ER) crossover to efficiently and effectively solve the PTSP. In addition, a mixed local search strategy by randomly selecting two different local search methods (i.e., 1-shift and 2-opt exchanges) is introduced to further enhance the effectiveness of the proposed MA for solving the PTSP. A set of numerical experiments based on both heterogeneous and homogeneous PTSP instances were conducted to test the validity of the proposed MA. The numerical results showed that the newly proposed MA enhanced the performance in terms of objective function value and/or computation time in most of the tested cases as compared to existing methods tested in previous studies. Moreover, the results indicated that incorporating mixed local search strategy into the MA can significantly increase the solution quality. These findings show the potential of the proposed MA in effectively and efficiently solving the large-scale PTSP.  " comment="This paper randomly selecting two different local search methods (i.e., 1-shift and 2-opt exchanges) is introduced to further enhance the effectiveness of the proposed MA for solving the PTSP." keywords="Liu, 2008"/>
  <article id="87" title="A self-adaptive cellular memetic algorithm for the DNA fragment assembly problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="88" title="A Memetic-Neural Approach to Discover Resources in P2P Networks" pages="113-129" loc="" type="article" year="2008" abstract="This chapter proposes a neural network based approach for solving the resource discovery problem in Peer to Peer (P2P) networks and an Adaptive Global Local Memetic Algorithm (AGLMA) for performing in training of the neural network. The neural network, which is a multi-layer perceptron neural network, allows the P2P nodes to efficiently locate resources desired by the user. The necessity of testing the network in various working conditions, aiming to obtain a robust neural network, introduces noise in the objective function. The AGLMA is a memetic algorithm which employs two local search algorithms adaptively activated by an evolutionary framework. These local searchers, having different features according to the exploration logic and the pivot rule, have the role of exploring decision space from different and complementary perspectives. Furthermore, the AGLMA makes an adaptive noise compensation by means of explicit averaging on the fitness values and a dynamic population sizing which aims to follow the necessity of the optimization process. The numerical results demonstrate that the proposed computational intelligence approach leads to an efficient resource discovery strategy and that the AGLMA outperforms an algorithm classically employed for executing the neural network training.  " comment="" keywords="Neri, 2008"/>
  <article id="89" title="A cost-benefit-based adaptation scheme for multimeme algorithms" pages="509-519" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="Memetic Algorithms are the most frequently used hybrid of Evolutionary Algorithms (EA) for real-world applications. This paper will deal with one of the most important obstacles to their wide usage: compared to pure EA, the number of strategy parameters which have to be adjusted properly is increased. A cost-benefit-based adaptation scheme suited for every EA will be introduced, which leaves only one strategy parameter to the user, the population size. Furthermore, it will be shown that the range of feasible sizes can be reduced drastically." comment="undefined" keywords="Jakob, 2007"/>
  <article id="90" title="Pheromone meme based immune clonal selection algorithm for function optimization" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="91" title="Fitness diversity based adaptive memetic algorithm for solving inverse problems of chemical kinetics" pages="2366-2373" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="This paper proposes the Fitness Diversity based Adaptive Memetic Algorithm (FIDAMA) for solving the problem of the inverse type consisting of retrieving chemical kinetics reaction rate coefficients in the generalised Arrhenius form based on the observed concentrations in a given range of temperatures of a limited set of species which describe the reaction mechanism. FIDAMA consists of the Evolutionary Framework and three Local Searchers adaptively governed by a novel fitness diversity based measure. Moreover, a certain simplification of the decision space was carried out without any deterioration in the result obtained. The numerical results preseted show the superiority of FIDAMA compared to the other published computational intelligence methods. " comment="The author mention that &amp;quot;The setting of &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;tau_3&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; should rely on the experimental observation that the successful evolution process is usually governed by a few superfit individuals which \'pull\' the rest of the population. This means that for the population to evolve successfully by its own means (i.e. by the evolutionary operators) the value of &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;tau_3&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; should lie somewhere within [0.1, 0.4]. However, the real optimal value for this interval would depend strongly on the fitness landscape under investigation. The situation when &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;tau_3 in &amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; [0.65, 1] looks high improbable for most fitness landscapes... The Authors have decided to[br]divide the interval &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;d_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; of the fitness values into 3 subintervals according to some heuristic rules. However, other variants of the proposed scheme can of course be the area of future research... any significant shift in the balance of points on the tails of the fitness values distribution would mean for &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;tau_3&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; tending to either 0 or 1&amp;quot;." keywords="Kononova, 2008"/>
  <article id="92" title="Entropy-based memetic particle swarm optimization for computing periodic orbits of nonlinear mappings" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="94" title="Accelerating differential evolution using an adaptive local search" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="95" title="Designing neural networks using PSO-based memetic algorithm" pages="219-224" loc="" type="article" year="2007" abstract="This paper proposes an effective particle swarm optimization (PSO) based memetic algorithm (MA) for designing artificial neural network. In the proposed PSO-based MA (PSOMA), not only the evolutionary searching mechanism of PSO characterized by individual improvement plus population cooperation and competition is applied to perform the global search, but also several adaptive high-performance faster training algorithms are employed to enhance the local search, so that the exploration and exploitation abilities of PSOMA can be well balanced. Moreover, an effective adaptive MetaLamarckian learning strategy is employed to decide which local search method to be used so as to prevent the premature convergence and concentrate computing effort on promising neighbor solutions. Simulation results and comparisons demonstrate the effectiveness and efficiency of the proposed PSOMA." comment="&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The author uses the Meta-Lamarckian Biased Roulette Wheel Meme Selection strategy to adaptively select the meme. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;four ANN training algorithms are utilized as the pool of local searches, including Powell-Beale, Scaled Conjugate Gradient, BFGS, and Levenberg-Marquardt algorithms&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;" keywords="Liu, 2007"/>
  <article id="96" title="An adaptive evolutionary algorithm with intelligent mutation local searchers for designing multidrug therapies for HIV" pages="219--235" loc="Volume 27, Number 3" type="article" year="2007" abstract="This paper proposes a novel Memetic Algorithm consisting of an Adaptive Evolutionary Algorithm (AEA) with three Intelligent Mutation Local Searchers (IMLSs) for designing optimal multidrug Structured Treatment Interruption (STI) therapies for Human Immunodeficiency Virus (HIV) infection. The AEA is an evolutionary algorithm with a dynamic parameter setting. The adaptive use of the local searchers helps the evolutionary process in the search of a global optimum. The adaptive rule is based on a phenotypical diversity measure of the population. The proposed algorithm has been tested for determining optimal 750-day pharmacological protocols for HIV patients. The pathogenesis of HIV is described by a system of differential equations including a model for an immune response. The multidrug therapies use reverse transcriptase inhibitor and protease inhibitor anti-HIV drugs. The medical protocol designed by the proposed algorithm leads to a strong immune response; the patient reaches a &amp;quot;healthy&amp;quot; state in one and half years and after this the STI medications can be discontinued. A comparison with a specific heuristic method and a standard Genetic Algorithm (GA) has been performed. Unlike the heuristic, the AEA with IMLSs does not impose any restrictions on the therapies in order to reduce the dimension of the problem. Unlike the GA, the AEA with IMLSs can overcome the problem of premature convergence to a suboptimal medical treatment. The results show that the therapies designed by the AEA lead to a &amp;quot;healthy&amp;quot; state faster than with the other methods. The statistical analysis confirms the computational effectiveness of the algorithm. [br]" comment="This paper uses the similar technique to (Caponia, 2007) in which &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;xi&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is used as the fitness diversity measure to adaptively select among a pool of memes" keywords="Neri, 2007"/>
  <article id="97" title="On the influence of phenotype plasticity on genotype diversity" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="98" title="Adaptation of iterated prisoner[quot]s dilemma strategies by evolution and learning" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="99" title="An adaptive global-local memetic algorithm to discover resources in P2P networks" pages="61-70" loc="ISBN 978-3-540-71804-8" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="This paper proposes a neural network based approach for solving the resource discovery problem in Peer to Peer (P2P) networks and an Adaptive Global Local Memetic Algorithm (AGLMA) for performing the training of the neural network. This training is very challenging due to the large number of weights and noise caused by the dynamic neural network testing. The AGLMA is a memetic algorithm consisting of an evolutionary framework which adaptively employs two local searchers having different exploration logic and pivot rules. Furthermore, the AGLMA makes an adaptive noise compensation by means of explicit averaging on the fitness values and a dynamic population sizing which aims to follow the necessity of the optimization process. The numerical results demonstrate that the proposed computational intelligence approach leads to an efficient resource discovery strategy and that the AGLMA outperforms two classical resource discovery strategies as well as a popular neural network training algorithm." comment="this paper is similar to &amp;quot;A memetic-neural approach to discover resources in P2P networks&amp;quot;" keywords="Neri, 2007"/>
  <article id="100" title="A Memetic Differential Evolution in Filter Design for Defect Detection in Paper Production" pages="320-329" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="" comment="undefined" keywords="Tirronen, 2007"/>
  <article id="101" title="Memetic algorithms for parallel code optimization" pages="33-61" loc="Volume 35, Number 1" type="article" year="2007" abstract="Discovering the optimum number of processors and the distribution of data on distributed memory parallel computers for a given algorithm is a demanding task. A memetic algorithm (MA) is proposed here to find the best number of processors and the best data distribution method to be used for each stage of a parallel program. Steady state memetic algorithm is compared with transgenerational memetic algorithm using different crossover operators and hill-climbing methods. A self-adaptive MA is also implemented, based on a multimeme strategy. All the experiments are carried out on computationally intensive, communication intensive, and mixed problem instances. The MA performs successfully for the illustrative problem instances." comment="" keywords="Ozcan, 2007"/>
  <article id="103" title="An effective PSO-based memetic algorithm for flow shop scheduling" pages="18-27" loc="Volume 37, Number 1" type="article" year="2007" abstract="This paper proposes an effective particle swarm optimization (PSO)-based memetic algorithm (MA) for the permutation flow shop scheduling problem (PFSSP) with the objective to minimize the maximum completion time, which is a typical non-deterministic polynomial-time (NP) hard combinatorial optimization problem. In the proposed PSO-based MA (PSOMA), both PSO-based searching operators and some special local searching operators are designed to balance the exploration and exploitation abilities. In particular, the PSOMA applies the evolutionary searching mechanism of PSO, which is characterized by individual improvement, population cooperation, and competition to effectively perform exploration. On the other hand, the PSOMA utilizes several adaptive local searches to perform exploitation. First, to make PSO suitable for solving PFSSP, a ranked-order value rule based on random key representation is presented to convert the continuous position values of particles to job permutations. Second, to generate an initial swarm with certain quality and diversity, the famous Nawaz-Enscore-Ham (NEH) heuristic is incorporated into the initialization of population. Third, to balance the exploration and exploitation abilities, after the standard PSO-based searching operation, a new local search technique named NEH$\\_$1 insertion is probabilistically applied to some good particles selected by using a roulette wheel mechanism with a specified probability. Fourth, to enrich the searching behaviors and to avoid premature convergence, a simulated annealing (SA)-based local search with multiple different neighborhoods is designed and incorporated into the PSOMA. Meanwhile, an effective adaptive meta-Lamarckian learning strategy is employed to decide which neighborhood to be used in SA-based local search. Finally, to further enhance the exploitation ability, a pairwise-based local search is applied after the SA-based search. Simulation results based on benchmarks demonstrate the effectiveness of the PSOMA. Additionally, the effects of some parameters on optimization performances are also discussed.[br]" comment="" keywords="Liu, 2007"/>
  <article id="104" title="Memetic algorithms for nurse rostering" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="105" title="A hybrid adaptive multi-objective memetic algorithm for 0/1 knapsack problem" pages="176-185" loc="" type="article" year="2005" abstract="A hybrid adaptive memetic algorithm for a multi-objective combinatorial optimization problem is proposed in this paper. Different solution fitness evaluation methods are hybridized to achieve global exploitation and exploration. At each generation, a wide diversified set of weights are used to search across all regions in objective space, and each weighted linear utility function is optimized with a simulated annealing. For a broader exploration, a grid-based technique is employed to discover the missing nondominated regions on existing tradeoff surface, and a Pareto-based local perturbation is used to reproduce additional good individuals trying to fill up the discontinuous areas. For better stability and convergence of the algorithm, the procedure is made dynamic and adaptive to online optimization conditions based upon a function of improvement ratio. Experiment results show the effectiveness of the proposed method on multi-objective 0/1 knapsack problems." comment="" keywords="Guo, 2005"/>
  <article id="106" title="A hybrid self-adjusted memetic algorithm for multi-objective optimization" pages="663-672" loc="Volume 3789" type="article" year="2005" abstract="A novel memetic algorithm for multi-objective optimization problems is proposed in this paper. The uniqueness of the method is that it hybridizes scalarizing selection with Pareto selection for exploitation and exploration. For extending the spread of solutions as quickly and fully as possible, the scalarizing functions defined by a wide diversified set of weights are used to go through all regions in objective space in the first phase at each generation. In the second phase, for intensifying search ability and achieving global exploration, a grid-based method is used to discover the gaps on existing tradeoff surface, and a fuzzy local perturbation is employed to reproduce additional &amp;quot;good&amp;quot; individuals in the missing areas. Both the exploitation and exploration are made dynamic and adaptive to online optimization conditions based on a function of progress ratio, ensuring better stability of the algorithm. Compared with several state-of-the-art approaches using the same set of multi-objective 0/1 knapsack problem instances, experiment results show that the proposed method perform better to some extent in terms of finding a near-Pareto front and well-extended nondominated set." comment="" keywords="Guo, 2005"/>
  <article id="107" title="Adaptive Reservoir Evolutionary Algorithm An evolutionary on-line adaptation scheme for global function optimization" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="108" title="Real-coded memetic algorithms with crossover hill-climbing" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="109" title="Self-adaptation in evolutionary algorithms for combinatorial optimisation" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="110" title="A memetic algorithm for dynamic design of wireless sensor networks" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="111" title="A memetic algorithm for test data generation of object-oriented software" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="112" title="An empirical study on the specification of the local search application probability in multiobjective memetic algorithms" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="113" title="Memetic algorithms for inexact graph matching" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="114" title="Memetic algorithm based fuzzy clustering" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="115" title="Designing memetic algorithms for real-world applications using self-imposed constraints" pages="3050-3057" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Memetic algorithms (MAs) combine the global exploration abilities of evolutionary algorithms with a local search to further improve the solutions. While a neighborhood can be easily defined for discrete individual representations, local search within real-valued domains requires an appropriate choice of the local search method. If the subject of optimization shows discontinuous behavior, a standard hill-climbing routine cannot be successfully applied. Thus, in this paper we present a general approach that defines a quasi-discrete neighborhood for real-valued variables by applying problem-specific selfimposed constraints. Thereby, knowledge about properties of good solutions can be easily integrated into the search process and discontinuous parts can be found. Satisfying results can be obtained faster while all important issues in the design of MAs are preserved." comment="" keywords="Michelitsch, 2008"/>
  <article id="116" title="MNFS-FPM A novel Memetic Neuro-fuzzy System based Financial Portfolio Management" pages="2554-2561" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Portfolio management consists of deciding what assets to include in a portfolio given the investor\'s objectives and changing market and economic conditions. The always difficult selection process includes identifying which assets to purchase, how much, and when. This paper presents a novel Memetic Neuro-fuzzy System for Financial Portfolio Management (MNFS-FPM) which emulates the thinking process of a rational investor and generates the optimal portfolio from a collection of assets based on a chosen investment style. The system consists mainly of two modules: the Generic Self-Organizing Fuzzy Neural Network realizing Yager inference (GenSoFNN-Yager), to predict the expected return of each asset, and a memetic algorithm using simplex local searches (MA-NM/SMD) to determine the optimal investment weight allocation for all assets in the portfolio. Experimental results on Dow Jones Industrial Average (DJIA) stocks show that the proposed system yields better performance compared to that of existing financial models: statistical mean-variance analysis and Capital Asset Pricing Model (CAPM)." comment="" keywords="Lumanpauw, 2008"/>
  <article id="117" title="Hybrid evolutionary algorithm for multilayer perceptron networks with competitive performance" pages="1620-1627" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Hybrid models combining neural networks and genetic algorithms have been studied recently with the goal of achieving either better performance of the resulting network or faster training. In this paper we deal with variants of genetic learning applied for the structure optimization and weights evolution of multi-layer perceptron networks. Several genetic operators are tested, including memetic-type local search, that produce good results in terms of network performace. It is shown, that combining evolutionary algorithms with neural networks can lead to better results than relying on neural networks alone in terms of the quality of the solution (both training and generalization error). Comparison to gradient algorithms in terms of time complexity is discussed which does not bring overly optimistic results sometimes met in literature." comment="" keywords="Neruda, 2008"/>
  <article id="118" title="Advances on protein folding simulations based on the lattice HP models with natural computing" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="119" title="Robust stability analysis of discrete time system via an optimization approach" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="120" title="A memetic algorithm for global induction of decision trees" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="121" title="Graph theoretical implementation of memetic algorithms in structural optimization of frame bracing layouts" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="122" title="A multi-tiered memetic multiobjective evolutionary algorithm for the design of quantum cascade lasers" pages="186-200" loc="Volume 4403" type="inproceedings" year="2006" abstract="Recent advances in quantum cascade lasers (QCLs) have enabled their use as (tunable) emission sources for chemical and biological spectroscopy, as well as allowed their demonstration in applications in medical diagnostics and potential homeland security systems. Finding the optimal design solution can be challenging, especially for lasers that operate in the terahertz region. The production process is prohibitive, so an optimization algorithm is needed to find high quality QCL designs. Past research attempts using multiobjective evolutionary algorithms (MOEAs) have found good solutions, but lacked a local search element that could enable them to find more effective solutions. This research looks at two memetic MOEAs that use a neighborhood search, Our baseline memetic MOEA used a simple neighborhood search, which is similar to other MOEA neighborhood searches found in the literature. Alternatively, our innovative multi-tiered memetic MOEA uses problem domain knowledge to change the temporal focus of the neighborhood search based on the generation. It is empirically shown that the multi-tiered memetic MOEA is able to find solutions that dominate the base-line memetic algorithm. Additional experiments suggest that using local search on only non-dominated individuals improves the effectiveness and efficiency of the algorithm versus applying the local search to dominated individuals as well. This research validates the importance of using multi-objective problem (MOP) domain knowledge in order to obtain the best results for a real world solution. It also introduces a new multi-tiered local search procedure that is able to focus the local search on specific critical elements of the problem at different stages in the optimization process. " comment="" keywords="Kleeman, 2006"/>
  <article id="123" title="Memetic algorithms for feature selection on microarray data" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="124" title="A memetic-clustering-based evolution strategy for traveling salesman problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="125" title="Local search in two-fold EMO algorithm to enhance solution similarity for multi-objective vehicle routing problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="126" title="An evolutionary algorithm with diversified crossover operator for the heterogeneous probabilistic TSP" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="127" title="A memetic algorithm for water distribution network design" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="128" title="An effective memetic algorithm with population management for the split delivery vehicle routing problem" pages="16-30" loc="" type="article" year="2007" abstract="This paper studies the Split Delivery Vehicle Routing problem (SDVRP), a variant of the VRP in which multiple visits to customers are allowed. This NP-hard problem is solved by a recent metaheuristic called Memetic Algorithm with Population Management or MA$|$PM. It consists in a genetic algorithm, combined with a local search procedure for intensification and a distance measure to control population diversity. Special moves dedicated to split deliveries are introduced in the local search. This solution approach is evaluated and compared with the tabu search algorithm of Archetti et al. (2006) and with lower bounds designed by Belenguer et al. (2000). Our method out-performs the tabu search both in solution quality and running time. On a set of 49 instances, it improves the best-known solution 32 times. The savings obtained confirm the interest and the power of the MA | PM.[br]" comment="" keywords="Boudia, 2007"/>
  <article id="129" title="A memetic algorithm with genetic particle swarm optimization and neural network for maximum cut problems" pages="297-306" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="In this paper, we incorporate a chaotic discrete Hopfield neural network (CDHNN), as a local search scheme, into a genetic particle swarm optimization (GPSO) and develop a memetic algorithm GPSO-CDHNN for the maximum cut problem. The proposed algorithm not only performs exploration by using the population-based evolutionary search ability of the GPSO, but also performs exploitation by using the CDHNN. Simulation results show that the proposed algorithm has superior ability for maximum cut problems." comment="Chaotic Discrete Hopfield Neural Network (CDHNN)" keywords="Wang, 2009"/>
  <article id="130" title="A memetic algorithm for reliability-based dynamic scheduling in heterogeneous computing environments" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="131" title="A memetic algorithm for the optimum communication spanning tree problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="132" title="A memetic approach to fuzzy job shop based on expectation model" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="133" title="A new evolutionary algorithm for the bi-objective minimum spanning tree" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="134" title="Evolutionary approaches to solve an integrated lot scheduling problem in the soft drink industry" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="135" title="Parallel multi-objective memetic RBFNNs design and feature selection for function approximation problems" pages="16-18" loc="Volume 72" type="article" year="2009" abstract="The design of Radial Basis Function Neural Networks (RBFNNs) still remains as a difficult task when they are applied to classification or to regression problems. The difficulty arises when the parameters that define an RBFNN have to be set, these are: the number of RBFs, the position of their centers and the length of their radii. Another issue that has to be faced when applying these models to real world applications is to select the variables that the RBFNN will use as inputs. The literature presents several methodologies to perform these two tasks separately, however, due to the intrinsic parallelism of the genetic algorithms, a parallel implementation will allow the algorithm proposed in this paper to evolve solutions for both problems at the same time. The parallelization of the algorithm not only consists in the evolution of the two problems but in the specialization of the crossover and mutation operators in order to evolve the different elements to be optimized when designing RBFNNs. The subjacent Genetic Algorithm is the Non-Sorting Dominated Genetic Algorithm II (NSGA-II) that helps to keep a balance between the size of the network and its approximation accuracy in order to avoid overtraining networks. Another of the novelties of the proposed algorithm is the incorporation of local search algorithms in three stages of the algorithm: initialization of the population, evolution of the individuals, and final optimization of the Pareto front. The initialization of the individuals is performed hybridizing clustering techniques with the Mutual Information theory (MI) to select the input variables. As the experiment will show, the synergy of the different paradigms and techniques combined by the presented algorithm allow to obtain very accurate models using the most significant input variables." comment="Levenberg-Mardquardt" keywords="Guillen, 2009"/>
  <article id="136" title="Markov blanket-embedded genetic algorithm for gene selection" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="137" title="Energy-aware topology control for wireless sensor networks using memetic algorithms" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="138" title="Optimal radiation pattern design of adaptive linear array antenna by phase and amplitude perturbations using memetic algorithms" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="139" title="Uplink MIMO-SDMA optimisation of smart antennas by phase-amplitude perturbations based on memetic algorithms for wireless and mobile communication systems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="140" title="Hybrid ant colony optimization using memetic algorithm for traveling salesman problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="141" title="Enhanced learning in fuzzy simulation models using memetic particle swarm optimization" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="142" title="A memetic PSO algorithm for scalar optimization problems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="143" title="Memetic algorithms parametric optimization for microlithography: Hybridization of genetic algorithms with a local optimizer for bound-constrained optimization problems" pages="201-239" loc="Volume 75" type="article" year="2007" abstract="Numerous physical models have been developed in order to describe the physical and chemical processes constituting the optical microlithography process. Many of these models depend on parameters that have to be calibrated against experimental data. An optimization routine using a genetic algorithm (GA) proved a feasible approach in order to find adequate model parameters. However, the high computation time and the need for a better reproducibility of the results suggest improvements of this approach. In this chapter we show that the application of the proposed memetic algorithm (MA) to the calibration of photoresist parameters is suited to improve both the convergence behavior and the reproducibility of results. As a GA is a model of Darwinian natural evolution, so can an MA be qualified as a model of cultural evolution. An MA can be characterized as a combination of interactive and individual search of a given population. From this general model, a variety of implementations can be derived. In this chapter, we will present a hybrid MA employing a GA and a method from the field of mathematical constrained optimization, the sequential quadratic programming (SQP) algorithm." comment="" keywords="Durar, 2007"/>
  <article id="144" title="A hybrid evolutionary heuristic for job scheduling on computational grids" pages="269-311" loc="" type="article" year="2007" abstract="In this chapter, we present a hybrid evolutionary metaheuristic based on memetic algorithms (MAs) and several local search algorithms. The memetic algorithm is used as the principal heuristic that guides the search and can use any of the 16 local search algorithms during the search process. The local search algorithms used in combination with the MA are obtained by fixing either the type of the neighborhood or the type of the move; they include swap/move based search, Hill Climbing, Variable Neighborhood Search, and Tabu Search. The proposed hybrid metaheuristic is implemented in C++ using a generic approach based on a skeleton for MAs. The implementation has been extensively tested in order to identify a set of appropriate values for the MA and local search parameters. We have comparatively studied the combination of MA with different local search algorithms in order to identify the best hybridization. Results are compared with the best known results for the problem in the evolutionary computing literature, namely the benchmark of Braun et al. (2001), which is known to be the most difficult benchmark for static instances of the problem. Our experimental study shows that the MA+ TS hybridization outperforms the combinations of MA with other local search algorithms considered in this work and also improves the results of Braun et al. for all considered instances. We also discuss some issues related to the fine tuning and experimenting of metaheuristics in a dynamic environment." comment="" keywords="Xhafa, 2007"/>
  <article id="145" title="Pareto evolutionary algorithm hybridized with local search for biobjective TSP" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="146" title="A memetic fingerprint matching algorithm" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="147" title="A memetic algorithm for the low autocorrelation binary sequence problem" pages="1226-1233" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="Finding binary sequences with low auto correlation is a very hard problem with many practical applications. In this paper we analyze several meta heuristic approaches to tackle the construction of this kind of sequences. We focus on two different local search strategies, steepest descent local search (SDLS) and tabu search (TS), and their use both as stand-alone techniques and embedded within a memetic algorithm (MA). Plain evolutionary algorithms are shown to perform worse than stand-alone local search strategies. However, a MA endowed with TS turns out to be a state-of-the-art algorithm: it consistently finds optimal sequences in considerably less time than previous approaches reported in the literature." comment="" keywords="Gallardo, 2007"/>
  <article id="148" title="Simultaneous optimization of production planning and inspection planning for flexible manufacturing systems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="149" title="Convergence of stochastic search algorithms to gap-free pareto front approximations" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="150" title="Using memetic algorithms with guided local search to solve assembly sequence planning" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="151" title="Resource leveling using Petrinet and memetic approach" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="152" title="Finding feasible timetables using group-based operators" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="153" title="A memetic algorithm using a trust-region derivative-free optimization with quadratic modelling for optimization of expensive and noisy black-box functions" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="154" title="Robust salting route optimization using evolutionary algorithms" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="155" title="Wrapper-filter feature selection algorithm using a memetic framework" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="156" title="A multiobjective memetic algorithm based on particle swarm optimization" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="157" title="A memetic algorithm for VLSI floorplanning" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="158" title="A memetic algorithm for multiple-drug cancer chemotherapy schedule optimization" pages="84-91" loc="Volume 37, Number 1" type="article" year="2007" abstract="This correspondence introduces a multidrug cancer chemotherapy model to simulate the possible response of the tumor cells under drug administration. We formulate the model as an optimal control problem. The algorithm in this correspondence optimizes the multidrug cancer chemotherapy schedule. The objective is to minimize the tumor size under a set of constraints. We combine the adaptive elitist genetic algorithm with a local search algorithm called iterative dynamic programming (IDP) to form a new memetic algorithm (MA-IDP) for solving the problem. MA-IDP has been shown to be very efficient in solving the multidrug scheduling optimization problem. " comment="" keywords="Tse, 2007"/>
  <article id="159" title="On the hybridization of memetic algorithms with branch-and-bound techniques" pages="77-83" loc="Volume 37, Number 1" type="article" year="2007" abstract="In this paper Branch-and-bound (BnB) and memetic algorithms represent two very different approaches for tackling combinatorial optimization problems. However, these approaches are compatible. In this correspondence, a hybrid model that combines these two techniques is considered. To be precise, it is based on the interleaved execution of both approaches. Since the requirements of time and memory in BnB techniques are generally conflicting, a truncated exact search, namely, beam search, has opted to be carried out. Therefore, the resulting hybrid algorithm has a heuristic nature. The multidimensional 0-1 knapsack problem and the shortest common supersequence problem have been chosen as benchmarks. As will be shown, the hybrid algorithm can produce better results in both problems at the same computational cost, especially for large problem instances." comment="" keywords="Gallardo, 2007"/>
  <article id="160" title="Evolutionary algorithms refining a heuristic A hybrid method for shared-path protections in WDM networks under SRLG constraints" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="161" title="A genetic algorithm with a Quasi-local search for the job shop problem with recirculation" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="162" title="Estimation of distribution algorithm with 2-opt local search for the quadratic assignment problem" pages="570-576" loc="ISBN 978-1-59593-697-4" type="inproceedings" year="2007" abstract="This chapter proposes a combination of estimation of distribution algorithm (EDA) and the 2-opt local search algorithm (EDA/LS) for the quadratic assignment problem (QAP). In EDA/LS, a new operator, called guided mutation, is employed for generating new solutions. This operator uses both global statistical information collected from the previous search and the location information of solutions found so far. The 2-opt local search algorithm is applied to each new solution generated by guided mutation. A restart strategy based on statistical information is used when the search is trapped in a local area. Experimental results on a set of QAP test instances show that EDA/LS is comparable with the memetic algorithm of Merz and Freisleben and outperforms estimation of distribution algorithm with guided local search (EDA/GLS). The proximate optimality principle on the QAP is verified experimentally to justify the rationale behind heuristics (including EDA/GLS) for the QAP. " comment="2-Opt" keywords="Salhi, 2007"/>
  <article id="163" title="An analysis of memetic crossover[quot]s impact on a population" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="164" title="A memetic algorithm for multi-criteria sequencing problem for a mixed-model assembly line in a JIT production system" pages="2993-2998" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2006" abstract="This paper presents a new mathematical model of mixed-model assembly lines (MMAL) to find the best sequences of product models in a just-in-time (JIT) production system. The objective is to minimize three criteria with their importance weights: (i) total utility work cost, (ii) total production rate variation cost, and (iii) total setup cost. Due to its NP-hardness, a memetic algorithm (MA) is proposed and its performance is compared with the Lingo 6 software. To validate the proposed model, a number of test problems are solved to verify the good ability of the proposed MA in terms of the solution quality and computational time. The results reveal that the MA finds promising results, especially in the case of large-sized problems. [br]" comment="2-Opt" keywords="Tavakkoli-Moghaddam, 2006"/>
  <article id="165" title="Optimal design of distributed databases" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="166" title="Feature selection and classification using flexible neural tree" pages="305-313" loc="Volume 70, Number 1-3" type="article" year="2006" abstract="The purpose of this research is to develop effective machine learning or data mining techniques based on flexible neural tree FNT. Based on the pre-defined instruction/operator sets, a flexible neural tree model can be created and evolved. This framework allows input variables selection, over-layer connections and different activation functions for the various nodes involved. The FNT structure is developed using genetic programming (GP) and the parameters are optimized by a memetic algorithm (MA). The proposed approach was applied for two real-world problems involving designing intrusion detection system (IDS) and for breast cancer classification. The IDS data has 41 inputs/features and the breast cancer classification problem has 30 inputs/features. Empirical results indicate that the proposed method is efficient for both input feature selection and improved classification rate. " comment="" keywords="Chen, 2006"/>
  <article id="167" title="Heuristics assisted detection in high speed wireless communication systems" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="168" title="Traffic engineering next generation IP networks using gene expression programming" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="169" title="The effect of local search on the constrained portfolio selection problem" pages="2368-2374" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2006" abstract="The portfolio selection problem is a prominent example for multi-objective optimization in financial engineering. While for some problem instances of the portfolio selection problem there are efficient optimization algorithms, other problem instances can only be addressed by means of meta-heuristics like evolutionary algorithms. These more complicated problem instances include portfolio selection with multiple quadratic objectives or with non-linear constraints, like cardinality constraints. Evolutionary algorithms allow hybridization with local search heuristics, resulting in so called memetic algorithms. Such memetic approaches to the portfolio selection problem seem to be an interesting alternative. Unfortunately, the interaction between the evolutionary global search and the local search heuristic is complicated and difficult to understand. In this paper we evaluate the hybridization of a multi-objective evolutionary algorithm and a quadratic programming local search on multiple instances of the constrained and unconstrained portfolio selection problem using a problem specific representation. This multi-objective memetic algorithm proves to be a two-edged approach: On the one hand it improves the convergence rate for some problem instances. While on other hand problem instances the local search causes a neutral search space and eventually premature convergence. This paper investigates this behavior more closely, offers a plausible explanation and also outlines a possible remedy. " comment="" keywords="Streichen, 2006"/>
  <article id="170" title="The school timetabling problem A focus on elimination of open periods and isolated classes" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="171" title="Multi-objective memetic algorithm applied to the automated synthesis of analog circuits" pages="258-267" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="In this paper, a Multi-objective Memetic Algorithm applied to the automated synthesis of analog circuits is proposed. The optimization of circuit topologies and their parameters are simultaneously carried out. A variable-size 2D circuit representation is used. In this approach, the initial solutions are created based on expert knowledge through the use of well-known building-blocks and rules-based coupling schemes. The proposed genetic operators are specific to 2D encoding and they are capable of fomenting a balance between diversity and convergence. A local search process - the Simulated Annealing method - is applied in order to improve the circuit parameters. The results show that the proposed method generates, with small populations and few generations, small well-structured circuits which accomplish the specifications." comment="" keywords="Dantas, 2006"/>
  <article id="172" title="A new memetic algorithm using particle swarm optimization and genetic algorithm" pages="122-129" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="We describe a new memetic algorithm scheme combining a genetic algorithm (GA) and a particle swarm optimization algorithm (PSO). This memetic scheme uses the basic dynamics of PSO instead of the concept of the survival of fittest (selection strategy) in GA. Even though the scheme does not use a selection strategy, it shows that the algorithm can find good results and can be an alternative approach for network based optimization problems. We test it in the context of a memetic algorithm applied to well known spanning tree based optimization problem, the degree constrained minimum spanning tree problem (DCMST). We compare with existing evolutionary algorithms (EAs), including EA using edge window decoder and EA using edge-set encoding, which represent the current state of the art on the DCMST. The new memetic algorithm demonstrates superior performance on the smaller and lower degree instances of the well-used \'Structured Hard\' DCMST problems, and similar performance on the larger and higher degree instances." comment="" keywords="Soak, 2006"/>
  <article id="173" title="A memetic approach to Golomb rulers" pages="252-261" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="Finding Golomb rulers is an extremely challenging optimization problem with many practical applications. This problem has been approached by a variety of search methods in recent years. We consider in this work a hybrid evolutionary algorithm that incorporates ideas from greedy randomized adaptive search procedures (GRASP), tabu-based local search methods (TS) and scatter search (SS). In particular, GRASP and TS are embedded into a SS algorithm to serve as initialization and restarting methods for the population and as improvement technique respectively. The resulting memetic algorithm significantly outperforms earlier approaches (including other hybrid EAs, as well as hybridizations of local search and constraint programming), finding optimal rulers where the mentioned techniques failed. " comment="" keywords="Cotta, 2006"/>
  <article id="174" title="A multi-level memetic/exact hybrid algorithm for the still life problem" pages="212-221" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="Bucket elimination (BE) is an exact technique based on variable elimination. It has been recently used with encouraging results as a mechanism for recombining solutions in a memetic algorithm (MA) for the still life problem, a hard constraint optimization problem based on Conway\'s game of life. This paper studies expanded multi-level models in which this exact/metaheuristic hybrid is further hybridized with branch-and-bound techniques. A novel variable clustering based recombination operator is also explored, with the aim of reducing the inherent time complexity of BE. Multi-parent recombination issues are analyzed as well. The obtained results are of higher quality than any previous metaheuristic approach, with large instances being solved to optimality. " comment="" keywords="Gallardo, 2006"/>
  <article id="175" title="Optimum design of surface acoustic wave filters based on the taguchi\'s quality engineering with a memetic algorithm" pages="292-301" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="For deciding suitable structures of surface acoustic wave (SAW) filters based on the computer simulation, the equivalent circuit model of interdigital transducer (IDT), which includes several uncertain constant parameters, is usually used. In order to cope with the imperfections of the optimum design caused by the inevitable dispersion of these constant parameters, a technique based on the Taguchi\'s quality engineering coupled with a memetic algorithm (MA) is presented. Besides the traditional Taguchi\'s two-step design approach maximizing the robustness of SAW filters before realizing their specified functions, the proposed MA enables us to improve their robustness and functions simultaneously" comment="" keywords="Tagawa, 2006"/>
  <article id="176" title="Scheduling social golfers with memetic evolutionary programming" pages="150-161" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="The social golfer problem (SGP) has attracted significant attention in recent years because of its highly symmetrical, constrained, and combinatorial nature. Nowadays, it constitutes one of the standard benchmarks in the area of constraint programming. This paper presents the first evolutionary approach to the SGP. We propose a memetic algorithm (MA) that combines ideas from evolutionary programming and tabu search. In order to lessen the influence of the high number of symmetries present in the problem, the MA does not make use of recombination operators. The search is thus propelled by selection, mutation, and local search. In connection with the latter, we analyze the effect of baldwinian and lamarckian learning in the performance of the MA. An experimental study shows that the MA is capable of improving results reported in the literature, and supports the superiority of lamarckian strategies in this problem. " comment="" keywords="Cotta, 2006"/>
  <article id="177" title="Effective computational reuse for energy evaluations in protein folding" pages="725-740" loc="Volume 15, Number 5" type="article" year="2006" abstract="Predicting native conformations using computational protein models requires a large number of energy evaluations even with simplified models such as hydrophobichydrophilic (HP) models. Clearly, energy evaluations constitute a significant portion of computational time. We hypothesize that given the structured nature of algorithms that search for candidate conformations such as stochastic methods, energy evaluation computations can be cached and reused, thus saving computational time and effort. In this paper, we present a caching approach and apply it to 2D triangular HP lattice model. We provide theoretical analysis and prediction of the expected savings from caching as applied this model. We conduct experiments using a sophisticated evolutionary algorithm that contains elements of local search, memetic algorithms, diversity replacement, etc. in order to verify our hypothesis and demonstrate a significant level of savings in computational effort and time that caching can provide." comment="" keywords="Santos, 2006"/>
  <article id="178" title="A memetic heuristic for the generalized quadratic assignment problem" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="179" title="Scheduling with memetic algorithms over the spaces of semi-active and active schedules" pages="" loc="" type="article" year="2009" abstract="" comment="" keywords=""/>
  <article id="180" title="A Tutorial for Competent Memetic Algorithms: Model, Taxonomy, and Design Issues" pages="474-488" loc="Volume 9, Issue 5" type="article" year="2005" abstract="The combination of evolutionary algorithms with local search was named &amp;quot;memetic algorithms&amp;quot; (MAs) (Moscato, 1989). These methods are inspired by models of natural systems that combine the evolutionary adaptation of a population with individual learning within the lifetimes of its members. Additionally, MAs are inspired by Richard Dawkin\'s concept of a meme, which represents a unit of cultural evolution that can exhibit local refinement (Dawkins, 1976). In the case of MA\'s, &amp;quot;memes&amp;quot; refer to the strategies (e.g., local refinement, perturbation, or constructive methods, etc.) that are employed to improve individuals. In this paper, we review some works on the application of MAs to well-known combinatorial optimization problems, and place them in a framework defined by a general syntactic model. This model provides us with a classification scheme based on a computable index D, which facilitates algorithmic comparisons and suggests areas for future research. Also, by having an abstract model for this class of metaheuristics, it is possible to explore their design space and better understand their behavior from a theoretical standpoint. We illustrate the theoretical and practical relevance of this model and taxonomy for MAs in the context of a discussion of important design issues that must be addressed to produce effective and efficient MAs." comment="undefined" keywords="Krosnogor, 2005"/>
  <article id="185" title="A comprehensive analysis of hyper-heuristics" pages="3-23" loc="Volume 12, Issue 1" type="article" year="2008" abstract="In this paper, Meta-heuristics such as simulated annealing, genetic algorithms and tabu search have been successfully applied to many difficult optimization problems for which no satisfactory problem specific solution exists. However, expertise is required to adopt a meta-heuristic for solving a problem in a certain domain. Hyperheuristics introduce a novel approach for search and optimization. A hyper-heuristic method operates on top of a set of heuristics. The most appropriate heuristic is determined and applied automatically by the technique at each step to solve a given problem. Hyper-heuristics are therefore assumed to be problem independent and can be easily utilized by non-experts as well. In this study, a comprehensive analysis is carried[br]out on hyper-heuristics. The best method is tested against genetic and memetic algorithms on fourteen benchmark functions. Additionally, new hyper-heuristic frameworks[br]are evaluated for questioning the notion of problem independence." comment="undefined" keywords="Ozcan, 2008"/>
  <article id="181" title="On evolution, search, optimization, GAs and martial arts: toward memetic algorithms" pages="" loc="Caltech Concurrent Computation" type="techreport" year="1989" abstract="" comment="undefined" keywords="Moscato, 1989"/>
  <article id="186" title="Fitness diversity based adaptation in multimeme algorithms: A comparative study" pages="2374-2381" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="This paper compares three different fitness diversity adaptations in Multimeme Algorithms (MmAs). These diversity indexes have been integrated within a MmA present in literature, namely Fast Adaptive Memetic Algorithm. Numerical results show that it is not possible to establish a superiority of one of these adaptive schemes over the others and choice of a proper adaptation must be made by considering features of the problem under study. More specifically, one of these adaptations outperforms the others in the presence of plateaus or limited range of variability in fitness values, another adaptation is more proper for landscapes having distant and strong basins of attraction, the third one, in spite of its mediocre average performance can occasionally lead to excellent results." comment="This paper is in CEC2007" keywords="Neri, 2008"/>
  <article id="182" title="Memetic algorithms: a short introduction" pages="219-234" loc="" type="article" year="1999" abstract="" comment="undefined" keywords="Moscato, 1999"/>
  <article id="183" title="Classification of Adaptive Memetic Algorithms: A Comparative Study" pages="141-152" loc="Volume 36, Issue 1" type="article" year="2006" abstract="Adaptation of parameters and operators represents one of the recent most important and promising areas of research in evolutionary computations; it is a form of designing self-configuring algorithms that acclimatize to suit the problem in hand. Here, our interests are on a recent breed of hybrid evolutionary algorithms typically known as adaptive memetic algorithms (MAs). One unique feature of adaptive MAs is the choice of local search methods or memes and recent studies have shown that this choice significantly affects the performances of problem searches. In this paper, we present a classification of memes adaptation in adaptive MAs on the basis of the mechanism used and the level of historical knowledge on the memes employed. Then the asymptotic convergence properties of the adaptive MAs considered are analyzed according to the classification. Subsequently, empirical studies on representatives of adaptive MAs for different type-level meme adaptations using continuous benchmark problems indicate that global-level adaptive MAs exhibit better search performances. Finally we conclude with some promising research directions in the area." comment="" keywords="Ong, 2006"/>
  <article id="184" title="Meta-Lamarckian Learning in Memetic Algorithms" pages="99-110" loc="Volume 8, Issue 2" type="article" year="2004" abstract="Over the last decade, memetic algorithms (MAs) have relied on the use of a variety of different methods as the local improvement procedure. Some recent studies on the choice of local search method employed have shown that this choice significantly affects the efficiency of problem searches. Given the restricted theoretical knowledge available in this area and the limited progress made on mitigating the effects of incorrect local search method choice, we present strategies for MA control that decide, at runtime, which local method is chosen to locally improve the next chromosome. The use of multiple local methods during a MA search in the spirit of Lamarckian learning is here termed Meta-Lamarckian learning. Two adaptive strategies for Meta-Lamarckian learning are proposed in this paper. Experimental studies with Meta-Lamarckian learning strategies on continuous parametric benchmark problems are also presented. Further, the best strategy proposed is applied to a real-world aerodynamic wing design problem and encouraging results are obtained. It is shown that the proposed approaches aid designers working on complex engineering problems by reducing the probability of employing inappropriate local search methods in a MA, while at the same time, yielding robust and improved design search performance.[br]" comment="undefined" keywords="Ong, 2004"/>
  <article id="187" title="Super-fit control adaptation in memetic differential evolution frameworks" pages="811--831" loc="Volume 13, Number 8-9" type="article" year="2009" abstract="This paper proposes the super-fit memetic differential evolution (SFMDE). This algorithm employs a differential evolution (DE) framework hybridized with three meta-heuristics, each having different roles and features. Particle Swarm Optimization assists the DE in the beginning of the optimization process by helping to generate a super-fit individual. The two other meta-heuristics are local searchers adaptively coordinated by means of an index measuring quality of the super-fit individual with respect to the rest of the population. The choice of the local searcher and its application is then executed by means of a probabilistic scheme which makes use of the generalized beta distribution. These two local searchers are the Nelder mead algorithm and the Rosenbrock Algorithm. The SFMDE has been tested on two engineering problems; the first application is the optimal control drive design for a direct current (DC) motor, the second is the design of a digital filter for image processing purposes. Numerical results show that the SFMDE is a flexible and promising approach which has a high performance standard in terms of both final solutions detected and convergence speed. " comment=" " keywords="Caponio, 2009"/>
  <article id="188" title="Towards an Adaptive Multimeme Algorithm for Parameter Optimisation Suiting the Engineers\' Needs" pages="132-141" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2006" abstract="Important factors for the easy usage of an Evolutionary Algorithm[br](EA) are numbers of fitness calculations as low as possible, its robustness, and[br]the reduction of its strategy parameters as far as possible. Multimeme Algorithms[br](MMA) are good candidates for the first two properties. In this paper a[br]cost-benefit-based approach shall be introduced for the adaptive control of both[br]meme selection and the ratio between local and global search. The latter is[br]achieved by adaptively adjusting the intensity of the search of the memes and[br]the frequency of their usage. It will be shown in which way the proposed kind[br]of adaptation fills the gap previous work leaves. Detailed experiments in the[br]field of continuous parameter optimisation demonstrate the superiority of the[br]adaptive MMA over the simple MA and the pure EA." comment="The earlier Jakob\'s paper on cost-benefit scheme" keywords="Jakob, 2006"/>
  <article id="189" title="Optimizing the efficiency of parameterized local search within global search: a preliminary study" pages="365-372" loc="Volume 1" type="inproceedings" year="2000" abstract="Application-specific, parameterized local search algorithms (PLSAs), in which optimization accuracy can be traded-off with run-time, arise naturally in many optimization contexts. We introduce a novel approach, called simulated heating, for systematically integrating parameterized local search into global search algorithms (GSAs) in general and evolutionary algorithms in particular. Using the framework of simulated heating, we investigate both static and dynamic strategies for systematically managing the trade-off between PLSA accuracy and optimization effort. We show quantitatively that careful management of this trade-off is necessary to achieve the full potential of a GSA/PLSA combination. Furthermore, we provide preliminary results which[br]demonstrate the effectiveness of our simulated heating techniques in the context of code optimization for embedded software implementation, a practical problem that involves vast and complex search spaces." comment="&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Basic Principles&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The authors introduce a technique, called &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;simnluted heating&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt;, that systematically incorporates parameterized local search into the framework of global search. Let &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; be a parameter in the local search (e.g. LS intensity). The idea of simulated heating can be summarized as follows: Instead of keeping &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; constant for the entire optimization process, &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is initially given a low value (leading to low LS cost &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;C(p)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; and accuracy &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;A(p)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;) and increase it at certain points in time (which in turn increases &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;C(p)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; and &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;A(b)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;). &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Benefit&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;According to the authors, If &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is fixed, each iteration of the overall optimization procedure requires approximately the same amount of time. In contrast, with simulated heating the time resources used per iteration are lower at the beginning and higher at the end. That is, in the first half of the time a greater number of iterations is performed than in the second half with regard to a single run.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;In other words, the goal is to focus on the global search at the beginning and to find promising regions first; for this phase, LS runs with low accuracy, which in turn allows an greater number of optimization steps of GS. Afterwards, more time is spent by LS in order to improve the solutions found So far and/or to assess them more accurately. As a consequence, fewer global search operations are possible during this phase of optimization. &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is systematically increased in the course of time. &amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The authors use the term simulated heating for this approach by analogy to simulated annealing where a &amp;quot;temperature&amp;quot; is continuously decreased according to a given cooling[br]scheme. However simulated heating has little similarity to the simulated annealing process&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Heating Scheme&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;The Heating Scheme &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;H(t)&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; for parameter &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; is a function of optimization iterations &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;t&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; that defines the value of &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; at different iteration &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;t&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]In realizing simulated heating, there are two fundamental ways of implementing a heating scheme &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;H&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;: by &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;static&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; or &amp;lt;b&amp;gt;dynamic&amp;lt;/b&amp;gt; adaptation mechanisms. In the first case, it is assumed that the heating scheme is fixed per optimization run. Thus, it may be computed at compile-time or directly before the actual optimization. In the[br]latter case, the heating scheme evolves during run-time, i.e., is computed during the optimization run. Hence, it may vary for different runs.[br][br]&amp;lt;h4&amp;gt;Dynamic Heating Schemes&amp;lt;/h4&amp;gt;[br]A set of values &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;p_1, p_2, cdots, p_i, cdots, p_m&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is defined for the parameter &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;p&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt;, where &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;p_1 &amp;lt; p_2 &amp;lt; cdots &amp;lt; p_i &amp;lt; cdots &amp;lt; p_m&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;ol&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fixed Number of Iterations Per Parameter value(FIP): [br]Here, the next parameter value &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;p_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is taken when for a number &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;tStag&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; of iterations the quality of the best solution in the solution candidate set has not improved. As a consequence, for each parameter a different amount of time may be considered until the stagnation condition is fulfilled.[br]&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;li&amp;gt;Fixed Amount of Time Per Parameter value(FTP): [br]In this case, the next parameter &amp;lt;m&amp;gt;p_i&amp;lt;/m&amp;gt; is taken when for &amp;lt;i&amp;gt;Tstag&amp;lt;/i&amp;gt; seconds the quality of the best solution in the solution candidate set has not improved. As a consequence, for each parameter a different number of iterations may be considered until the stagnation condition is fulfilled.[br]&amp;lt;/li&amp;gt;[br]&amp;lt;/ol&amp;gt;[br]" keywords="Zitzler, 2000"/>
  <article id="190" title="Systematic integration of parameterized local search into evolutionary algorithms" pages="137-155" loc="Volume 8,  Issue 2" type="article" year="2004" abstract="Application-specific, parameterized local search algorithms (PLSAs), in which optimization accuracy can be traded off with run time, arise naturally in many optimization contexts.We introduce a novel approach, called simulated heating, for systematically integrating parameterized local search into evolutionary algorithms (EAs). Using the framework of simulated heating, we investigate both static and dynamic strategies for systematically managing the tradeoff between PLSA accuracy and optimization effort. Our goal is to achieve maximum solution quality within a fixed optimization time budget. We show that the simulated heating technique better utilizes the given optimization time resources than standard hybrid methods that employ fixed parameters, and that the technique is less sensitive to these parameter settings. We apply this framework to three different[br]optimization problems, compare our results to the standard hybrid.[br]methods, and show quantitatively that careful management[br]of this tradeoff is necessary to achieve the full potential of an[br]EA/PLSA combination." comment="&amp;lt;p&amp;gt;(Bambha, 2004) proposes an enhanced version of simulated heating (Zitzler, 2000) which[br]also takes into account the success of previous local search applications.&amp;lt;/p&amp;gt;[br][br]In the dynamic simulated heating, (at least) two optimization parameters are not fixed and may vary for different paramerized local search algorithm (PLSA) parameters. One of the variable parameters is determined dynamically during runtime according to a predefined criterion. Here, the criterion is whether an improvement with regard to[br]the solutions generated can be observed during a certain time interval (measured in seconds, number of solutions generated, or number of iterations performed). The time constraint is defined in terms of the remaining variable parameter." keywords="Bambha, 2004"/>
  <article id="191" title="Self Generating Metaheuristics in Bioinformatics: The Proteins Structure" pages="181-201" loc="Volume 5, Number 2" type="article" year="2004" abstract="In this paper, we describe the application of a so called &amp;quot;Self-Generating&amp;quot; Memetic Algorithm to the Maximum Contact Map Overlap problem (MAX-CMO). The maximum overlap of contact maps is emerging as a leading modeling technique to obtain structural alignment among pairs of protein structures. Identifying structural alignments (and hence similarity among proteins) is essential to the correct assessment of the relation between proteins structure and function. A robust methodology for structural comparison could have impact on the process of rational drug design. The Self-Generating Memetic Algorithm we present in this work evolves concurrently both the solutions (i.e. proteins alignments) and the local search move operators that it needs to solve the problem instance at hand. The concurrent generation of local search strategies and solutions allows the Memetic Algorithm to produce better results than those given by a Genetic Algorithm and a Memetic Algorithm with human-designed local searchers. The approach has been tried in four different data sets (1 data set composed of randomly generated proteins and the other 3 data sets with real world proteins) with encouraging results. " comment="" keywords="Krasnogor, 2004"/>
  <article id="192" title="A study on the use of &#x201D;self-generation&#x201D; in memetic algorithms" pages="53-76" loc="Volume 3, Number 1" type="article" year="2004" abstract="A vast number of very successful applications of Global-Local Search Hybrids have been reported in the literature in the last years for a wide range of problem domains. The majority of these papers report the combination of highly specialized pre-existing local searchers and usually purpose-specific global operators (e.g. genetic operators in an Evolutionary Algorithm). In this paper we concentrate on one particular class of Global-Local Search Hybrids, Memetic Algorithms (MAs), and we describe the implementation of &amp;quot;self-generating&amp;quot; mechanisms to produce the local searches the MA uses. This implementation is tested in two problems, NK-Landscape Problems and the Maximum Contact Map Overlap Problem (MAX-CMO)." comment="" keywords="Krasnogor, 2004"/>
  <article id="193" title="Memes, self-generation and nurse rostering" pages="85-104" loc="" type="article" year="2006" abstract="This paper presents an empirical study on memetic algorithms in two parts. In the first part, the details of the memetic algorithm experiments with a set of well known benchmark functions are described. In the second part, a heuristic template is introduced for solving timetabling problems. Two adaptive heuristics that utilize a set of constraint-based hill climbers in a co-operative manner are designed based on this template. A hyper-heuristic is a mechanism used for managing a set of low-level heuristics. At each step, an appropriate heuristic is chosen and applied to a candidate solution. Both adaptive heuristics can be considered as hyper-heuristics. Memetic algorithms employing each hyper-heuristic separately as a single hill climber are experimented on a set of randomly generated nurse rostering problem instances. Moreover, the standard genetic algorithm and two self-generating multimeme memetic algorithms are compared to the proposed memetic algorithms and a previous study." comment="" keywords="Ozcan, 2006"/>
  <article id="194" title="A memetic algorithm for dynamic multiobjective optimization" pages="353-367" loc="Volume 171" type="article" year="2009" abstract="Dynamic multi-objective optimization (DMO) is one of the most challenging class of multi-objective optimization problems where the objective function(s) change over time and the optimization algorithm is required to identify the corresponding Pareto optimal solutions with minimal time lag. DMO has received very little attention in the past and none of the existing multi-objective algorithms perform too well on the set of newly proposed DMO test problems. In this chapter, we introduce a memetic algorithm (MA) to deal with such class of problems. The memetic algorithm employs an orthogonal epsilon-constrained formulation to deal with multiple objectives and a sequential quadratic programming (SQP) solver is embedded as its local search mechanism to improve the rate of convergence. The performance of the memetic algorithm is compared with an evolutionary algorithm (EA) embedded with a Sub-EA on two benchmarks FDA1 and modified FDA2. The memetic algorithm consistently outperforms the evolutionary algorithm with Sub-EA for both FDA1 and modified FDA2 for all problem sizes. A variational study on the effect of the number of SQP iterations on the behavior of MA is included to highlight the benefits offered by MA for such class of problems." comment="" keywords="Ray, 2009"/>
  <article id="195" title="Fitness landscapes: royal road functions" pages="B.2.7.5:1&#x2013;25" loc="" type="article" year="1997" abstract="An important goal of research on genetic algorithms (GAs) is to understand the class of[br]problems for which GAs are most suited, and in particular, the class of problems on which[br]they will outperform other search algorithms such as gradient methods. We have developed[br]a class of &#xAF;tness landscapes|the \\Royal Road&amp;quot; functions (Mitchell, Forrest, and Holland[br]1992; Forrest and Mitchell 1993)|that isolate some of the features of &#xAF;tness landscapes[br]thought to be most relevant to the performance of GAs. Our goal in constructing these[br]landscapes is to understand in detail how such features a&#xAE;ect the search behavior of GAs[br]and to carry out systematic comparisons between GAs and other search methods." comment="" keywords="Mitchell, 1997"/>
  <article id="196" title="Probabilistic and deterministic local search for solving the binary multiknapsack problem" pages="33: 2, 155-166" loc="" type="article" year="1995" abstract="Results of extensive computational experiments aimed at comparing performance quality (accuracy of an approximate soiurion and the running time) of thc Threshold Accept (TA) approach versus the Simulated Annealing (SA) and a Greedy-Local improvement Search (GLS) approaches are presented. This comparison is done on a large set of test examples that represent the binary Multi-Knapsack Problem (MKPI). It appears that the best accuracy results are obtained for the TA algorithm. Purely deterministic search is only slightly[br]wane in accuracy, but remarkably better in the running time. comparing to both SA and TA." comment="" keywords="Bertocchi, 1995"/>
  <article id="197" title="The oil drilling model and iterative deepening genetic annealing algorithm for the traveling salesman problem" pages="169-184" loc="Volume 144" type="article" year="2009" abstract="In this work, we liken the solving of combinatorial optimization problems under a prescribed computational budget as hunting for oil in an unexplored ground. Using this generic model, we instantiate an iterative deepening genetic annealing (IDGA) algorithm, which is a variant of memetic algorithms. Computational results on the traveling salesman problem show that IDGA is more effective than standard genetic algorithms or simulated annealing algorithms or a straightforward hybrid of them. Our model is readily applicable to solve other combinatorial optimization problems. " comment="2-Opt" keywords="Lau, 2009"/>
  <article id="198" title="A hybrid meta heuristic algorithm for bi-objective minimum cost flow (BMCF) problem" pages="1056 - 1062" loc="Volume 40, Number 10" type="article" year="2009" abstract="In this paper, we study the bi-objective minimum cost flow (BMCF) problem which can be categorized as multi objective minimum cost flow problems. Generally, the exact computation of the efficient frontier is intractable and there may exist an exponential number of extreme non-dominated objective vectors. Hence, it is better to employ an approximate method to compute solutions within reasonable time. Therefore, we propose a hybrid meta heuristic algorithm (memetic algorithm hybridized with simulated annealing MA/SA) to develop an efficient approach for solving this problem. In order to show the efficiency of the proposed MA/SA some problems have been generated and solved by both the MA/SA and an exact method. It is perceived from this evaluation that the proposed MA/SA outputs are very close to the exact solutions. It is shown that when the number of arcs and nodes exceed 30 (large problems) the MA/SA model will be more preferred because of its strongly shorter computational time in comparison with exact methods." comment="" keywords="Ebrahim, 2009"/>
  <article id="199" title="A memetic approach to the automatic design of high-performance analog integrated circuits" pages="1-24" loc="Volume 14, Number 3" type="article" year="2009" abstract="This article introduces an evolution-based methodology, named memetic single-objective evolutionary algorithm (MSOEA), for automated sizing of high-performance analog integrated circuits. Memetic algorithms may achieve higher global and local search ability by properly combining operators from different standard evolutionary algorithms. By integrating operators from the differential evolution algorithm, from the real-coded genetic algorithm, operators inspired by the simulated annealing algorithm, and a set of constraint handling techniques, MSOEA specializes in handling analog circuit design problems with numerous and tight design constraints. The method has been tested through the sizing of several analog circuits. The results show that design specifications are met and objective functions are highly optimized. Comparisons with available methods like genetic algorithm and differential evolution in conjunction with static penalty functions, as well as with intelligent selection-based differential evolution, are also carried out, showing that the proposed algorithm has important advantages in terms of constraint handling ability and optimization quality.[br]" comment="" keywords="Liu, 2009"/>
  <article id="200" title="Finding low autocorrelation binary sequences with memetic algorithms" pages="1252 - 1262" loc="Volume 9, Number 4" type="article" year="2009" abstract="This paper deals with the construction of binary sequences with low autocorrelation, a very hard problem with many practical applications. The paper analyzes several metaheuristic approaches to tackle this kind of sequences. More specifically, the paper provides an analysis of different local search strategies, used as stand-alone techniques and embedded within memetic algorithms. One of our proposals, namely a memetic algorithm endowed with a Tabu Search local searcher, performs at the state-of-the-art, as it consistently finds optimal sequences in considerably less time than previous approaches reported in the literature. Moreover, this algorithm is also able to provide new best-known solutions for large instances of the problem. In addition, a variant of this algorithm that explores only a promising subset of the whole search space (known as skew-symmetric sequences) is also analyzed. Experimental results show that this new algorithm provides new best-known solutions for very large instances of the problem. " comment="" keywords="Gallardo, 2009"/>
  <article id="201" title="Memetic algorithms with variable-depth search to overcome local optima" pages="787-794" loc="ISBN 978-1-60558-130-9" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Variable-depth search (shortly VDS) is well-known as LinKernighan strategy for the TSP and Kernighan-Lin for graph partitioning. The basic idea is to make a sequence of local moves and to freeze all moved combinatorial objects to prevent the search from looping. VDS stops when no further local move is possible and returns a best found solution. We analyze memetic algorithms with VDS for three binary combinatorial problems: Mincut, Knapsack, and Maxsat. More precisely, we focus on simply structured problem instances containing local optima that are very hard to overcome. Many common trajectory-based algorithms fail to find a global optimum: the (1+1) EA, iterated local search, and simulated annealing need exponential time with high probability. However, memetic algorithms using VDS easily manage to find a global optimum in expected polynomial time. These results strengthen the usefulness of memetic algorithms with VDS from a theoretical perspective. " comment="Variable Depth Search" keywords="Sudholt, 2008"/>
  <article id="202" title="Combination of genetic algorithms and evolution strategies with self-adaptive switching" pages="281-307" loc="Volume 171" type="article" year="2009" abstract="For tackling an multi-objective optimization problem (MOP), evolutionary computation (EC) gathers much attention due to its population-based approach where several solutions can be obtained simultaneously. Since genetic algorithm (GA) and evolution strategy (ES) are often used in EC, we discuss only GA and ES in this chapter. Although both of them have global and local search capability, theoretical/empirical analysis reveals that GA is rather global search and ES is rather local search on MOP. These facts are related to how to generate offspring, i.e. crossover in GA and mutation in ES. On MOP, the crossover in GA and the mutation in ES generate differently distributed offspring. If mating in the crossover is not restricted, the crossover in GA can generate new offspring globally due to combination of parents which converge different points. Oppositely, the mutation in ES can generate the similar offspring with parent, i.e. locally distributed new offspring, because the offspring is generated by adding normally distributed random values to the parent. Recently, memetic algorithm, which combines GA with local search algorithm, is popular due to its performance. Since ES on MOP works as local search, we combine GA with ES as one of memetic algorithms in this chapter. This algorithm is called as hybrid representation. Several issues caused by the combination of GA and ES are discussed, e.g. the discretization error, self-adaptation and adaptive switching. Experiments are conducted on five well-known test functions using six different performance indices. The results show that the hybrid representation exhibits better and more stable performance than the original GA/ES.[br]" comment="" keywords="Okabe, 2009"/>
  <article id="203" title="Memetic differential evolution trained neural networks for nonlinear system identification" pages="" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2008" abstract="Several gradient-based approaches such as back-propagation, conjugate gradient and Levenberg Marquardt (LM) methods have been developed for training the neural network (NN) based systems. Still, in some situations, like multimodal cost function, these procedures may lead to some local minima, therefore, the evolutionary algorithms (EAs) based procedures were considered as a promising alternative. In this paper we focus on a memetic algorithm based approach for training the neural networks. We use the memetic algorithm (MA) for training the multilayer perceptrons as applied to nonlinear system identification. The proposed memetic algorithm is an alternative to gradient search methods, such as back-propagation, which have inherent limitations of many local optima. Here we have studied the identification of a nonlinear system using five different algorithms namely Back-propagation (BP), Genetic Algorithm (GA), Differential Evolution (DE), Genetic Algorithm Back-propagation (GABP), along with the proposed Differential Evolution plus Back-propagation (DEBP) approaches. In the proposed system identification scheme, we have exploited two global search methods namely genetic algorithm (GA), and differential evolution (DE). These two global search methods have been hybridized with the gradient descent method i.e. the back propagation (BP) algorithm. The local search BP algorithm is used as an operator for genetic algorithm and differential evolution. These algorithms have been tested on a standard benchmark problem for nonlinear system identification to prove their efficacy. " comment="Back Propagation Training LS" keywords="Subudhi, 2008"/>
  <article id="204" title="VLSI architecture for fast memetic vector quantizer design on reconfigurable hardware" pages="513-524" loc="" type="inproceedings" year="2009" abstract="A novel hardware architecture for memetic vector quantizer (VQ) design is presented in this paper. The architecture uses steady-state genetic algorithm (GA) for global search, and C-means algorithm for local refinement. It adopts a shift register based circuit for accelerating mutation and crossover operations for steady state GA operations. It also uses a pipeline architecture for the hardware implementation of C-means algorithm. The proposed architecture has been embedded in a softcore CPU for physical performance measurement. Experimental results show that the proposed architecture is an effective alternative for VQ optimization attaining both high performance and low computational time. " comment="C-means" keywords="Weng, 2009"/>
</mcarticles>
